Andy Chou

(619) 519-9644 | andychchou@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/andychchou/ | github.com/andychchou | San Diego, CA

SUMMARY

Full stack developer with experience in software development, cloud computing, and systems engineering.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: JavaScript, Python, Java, C#

Frameworks and Libraries: React, React Native, Redux, Bootstrap, SCSS, jQuery, Node.js, Express.js

Database, OS, IDE: MongoDB, DynamoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Linux, Visual Studio, Android Studio, Eclipse

Cloud and Web: AWS EC2, AWS Lambda, API Gateway, Heroku, REST API, Postman, WebSockets

More Technologies: Git/GitHub, virtual machines, Cisco Modeling Labs, containerization, Agile methodologies, CI/CD,

deployment, automation, scripting, network and systems engineering, software testing, DevOps

Personal Skills: Team and personnel management, client collaboration, project planning

PROJECTS

Personal Portfolio - andvchchou.github.io

• A responsive web page built utilizing Bootstrap and JavaScript.

Table Top Town - tabletoptown.herokuapp.com

• A web application with a table-top theme, built using React and Redux on the frontend, along with a Node.js server on the backend. The server utilizes Express.js and communicates with a remote MongoDB database.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Innovative Defense Technologies, San Diego, CA

Associate Software Engineer

Apr 2022 - Present

- Developed and tested Java applications, including deployment and integration at the customer site.
- Created virtual simulations of network environments and conducted stress testing of various systems.
- Improved automation of network communication between systems on both virtual and physical networks.
- Generated documentation during the development process to help guide other team members.

Novartis, San Diego, CA

Process Science Engineer

Nov 2020 - Apr 2022

- Conducted process development and engineering for multiple bioreactor designs.
- Facilitated inter-department communication to implement improvements to laboratory operations.

Abzena, San Diego, CA

Senior Process Development Associate

May 2019 - Nov 2020

- Managed a team of process development associates and scheduled responsibilities for staff members.
- Coordinated with clients on projects, including design of experiments and project proposals.
- Implemented computer automation of cell culture operations as well as data processing.

Process Development Associate

Jul 2017 - May 2019

• Utilized Design of Experiments (DoE) and multivariate data analysis for process optimization.

Production Associate

Apr 2016 – Jul 2017

Operated stirred tank and wave bioreactors in upstream cell culture manufacturing.

EDUCATION

Nucamp Coding

Full Stack Web and Mobile App Development

May 2021 - Nov 2021

Relevant courses: HTML/CSS/JS, Bootstrap, React, React Native, Node/Express, MongoDB

University of California, San Diego

Bachelor of Science in Biochemistry, Department of Chemistry

2011 – 2015

Relevant courses: Multivariable Calculus, Differential Equations, Statistics, Quantum Mechanics